Nick Trefz

Brooklyn, NY 860.469.5618 ntrefz@double9s.com

Portfolio

http://www.nicktrefz.com

Skills

- 8 years of graphic and web design
- 8 years expert level HTML/XHTML experience, now including HTML5
- 8 years expert level CSS experience, now including CSS3
- 5 years intermediate level JavaScript experience, including the jQuery library
- 8 years expert level Adobe Photoshop experience
- 8 years intermediate level Adobe Illustrator experience
- 4 years expert level Flash experience, including animation, ActionScript 2.0/3.0 development, XML integration, and streaming video
- 2 years of managerial duties, delegating work to up to 2 subordinates

Professional Experience

Time. Inc - New York, NY

Front-end Developer

August 2010 to Present

- Part of a team of designers and developers rebuilding Time's myrecipes.com web site
- Built the Real Simple mobile site in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery, all on schedule
- Collaborated directly with designers and back-end developers
- Fixed hundreds of bugs throughout development using CollabNet project tracking
- Added several features to Health.com, including Facebook and Twitter integration

Circle One Marketing - Norwalk, CT

Web Designer & Developer

April 2010 to July 2010

- Developed client web site using existing elements and mockups for new content
- Bug tested and improved HTML, CSS, and iQuery elements
- Developed custom Flash AS3 solution, built to communicate with JavaScript controls

Newssift - Stamford, CT Web Designer & Developer

September 2009 to December 2009

- Designed and developed a full dashboard front-end
- Integrated licensed charting tools, using Flash and XML feeds
- Integrated iQuery UI elements and created my own text truncator

REZ-1 - Newton, MA

Web Designer & Developer

June 2009 to July 2009

- Designed, built, and documented a full web app UI redesign in 3 weeks
- Integrated Apache Tapestry styles
- Created several color schemes, swappable through a single stylesheet include

CashStar - Portland, ME

Web Designer & Developer

November 2008 to March 2009

- Identified and fixed existing bugs (display issues, browser incompatibility, etc.), collaborating with managers via an integrated bug tracking system
- Redesigned user interface flow to fix targeted problems
- Built the prototype for a custom image uploading & cropping interface

The Dakota Group - Wilton, CT

Web Designer & Developer

August 2008 to October 2008

- Built interactive Flash marketing material, including video integration and animation (both timeline-based and ActionScript-based)
- Processed Photoshop mock ups into HTML, including the necessary CSS and images
- Collaborated with account managers and clients to create and update web site content

TopCoder - Glastonbury, CT

Lead Web Designer & Developer

June 2003 to July 2008

- Overhauled the UI of the entire TopCoder site (visual style, navigation, content)
- Collaborated daily with developers, sales, and management
- Updated TopCoder web sites to adhere to XHTML and CSS compliance
- Produced sound and video materials for both online and on-site marketing
- Analyzed web site metrics using Google Analytics and heat mapping software
- Worked with clients such as Google, Microsoft, Yahoo, AOL, Amazon, Intel, AMD, VeriSign, Verizon, British Telecom, Bloomberg, NVIDIA, and the NSA

Education

University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT Graduated Spring 2003 Bachelor of Science in Mathematics

Summary of Qualifications

I have the creativity to bring effective solutions to the table and the knowledge, experience and discipline to realize those solutions. Good ideas can get lost on the way from concept to execution, from designer to developer, so it helps to have someone who speaks the languages of both fields of expertise. The artist and the engineer.

References

Available on request.